<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Kawa Entertainment: VTuber NewsDrop Feed</title>
        <link>https://kawaentertainment.com/</link>
        <description>We are an "adoption" style Vtuber Agency, focusing on Technology. Our mission is to develop our talents and the entire vtubing community.</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 23:26:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>Gridsome Feed Plugin</generator>
        <atom:link href="https://kawaentertainment.com/news-feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nijisanji EN at Animate Cafe]]></title>
            <link>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/nijisanji-en-at-animate-cafe/</link>
            <guid>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/nijisanji-en-at-animate-cafe/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 20:35:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Part of NewsDrop’s activities is to feature various VTuber-related events across the globe, starting of course, in Japan, where the trend blew up. Slime alien VTuber and Kawa colleague PiaPi Yuefo shares her experience at the recent [Nijisanji EN Animate Cafe](https://cafe.animate.co.jp/event/nijisanji-en2208/) collaboration.

This cafe collab features Nijisanji EN livers Pomu Rainpuff (LazuLight), Selen Tatsuki (Obsydia), Reimu Endou (Ethyria), Ike Eveland, Shu Yamino and Luca Kaneshiro (Luxiem).

![](/src/assets/content/images/20220821_122555.jpg)  

Pia was there to help a friend, Pomu obsessed cosplayer [@RoReRuRu](https://twitter.com/roreruru), get lucky in scoring some randomized Pomu merch.

<album>

![](/src/assets/content/images/20220821_123723.jpg)

![](/src/assets/content/images/20220821_123916.jpg)

![](/src/assets/content/images/20220821_124131.jpg)

![](/src/assets/content/images/20220821_123516.jpg)

![](/src/assets/content/images/20220821_123508.jpg)

![](/src/assets/content/images/20220821_121724.jpg)

</album>

The Animate Collab Cafe serves drinks, desserts, and meals based on the VTubers of Nijisanji EN. Though some collabs put on by the Animate Cafe feature a dish each per character, this time around they opted to group the trio of girls and boys into two separate lunch plates and dessert plates. However, each was featured in a drink based on them, so you could grab the taste of your _oshi_ to wash it down!

![](/src/assets/content/images/20220821_125116.jpg)

Inside the cafe were 21 tables, each reserved for a pair. Seats are filled through an online reservation system, so you have to reserve your time slot in advance (There are walk-ins, but only become available if a pair doesn’t show). Doing so will also help you, especially if there are pre-order items only, as they will ask for your shipping address for future delivery.

![](/src/assets/content/images/20220821_123032.jpg)

One of Ruru’s goals was to add more items to her Pomu Rainpuff shrine, but was she able to secure the items? Unfortunately, the group came up dry in their random coaster drawings, pulling 3 Ike coasters, 2 Selen, 2 Reimu, and 1 Luca. No Pomu makes for a sad Ruru!

![](/src/assets/content/images/20220821_122719.jpg)

However, fret not because this particular Animate Cafe is located at Ikebukuro, also known as Otome Road, or the Akihabara for women/_fujoshi_! As such, coaster trades were plentiful with other guests! “_Most people around us had brought the men’s plate and men’s dessert and various male talents’ drinks. They were more than happy to surrender the Pomu goods to us in exchange for a chap or two!_”

Did we forget to mention that the Ninisani gag is made canon here?

<album>

![](/src/assets/content/images/20220821_132122.jpg)

![](/src/assets/content/images/20220821_132207.jpg)

![](/src/assets/content/images/20220821_130344.jpg)

</album>

***

The Nijisanji EN Animate Cafe collaboration is offered at Animate Cafe’s Ikebukuro No. 3 and Nagoya no. 2 branches until August 30.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hololive Would Like to Try Out South America, European Markets in the Future]]></title>
            <link>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/hololive-would-like-to-try-out-south-america-european-markets-in-the-future/</link>
            <guid>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/hololive-would-like-to-try-out-south-america-european-markets-in-the-future/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 17:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Anime News Network has posted their [interview](https://www.animenewsnetwork.com/convention/2022/crunchyroll-expo/interview-with-covercorp-ceo-motoaki-tanigo/.188262) with COVER Corporation CEO Motoaki Tanigo (YAGOO) at Crunchyroll Expo 2022. Among the questions asked is a potential entry into other markets:

> "\[...\] Right now, Japanese anime is big all over the world, so there are a lot of really strong markets. I don't have extensive knowledge about the international scene, but there are places like South America or Europe where a lot of anime are localized, and which are really interesting to me. We would like to try out those markets, and if things go well, we may also localize for those markets and foster talents from there."

Several VTubers originated from South America, such as VShojo's [Ironmouse](https://www.twitch.tv/ironmouse), [Nimu Spacecat](https://twitter.com/ThisNimu) and Mexican VTuber [PARRA](https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCbbk-UQsfmT-etWqU9LOcOg). Europe also enjoys a variety of VTubers such as Live2D artist [Dyarikku](https://www.twitch.tv/dyarikku), Storyteller [Merryweather](https://www.twitch.tv/merryweather), Illustrator [Saruei](https://www.twitch.tv/saruei), and even Hololive English's [Takanashi Kiara](https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCHsx4Hqa-1ORjQTh9TYDhww) who hails from Austria.

_Photo: COVER Corp._]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cosplay Mania 2022 to Host Moona Hoshinova and Pavolia Reine]]></title>
            <link>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/cosplay-mania-2022-to-host-moona-hoshinova-and-pavolia-reine/</link>
            <guid>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/cosplay-mania-2022-to-host-moona-hoshinova-and-pavolia-reine/</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 16:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Aside from Hololive Indonesia's [Ayunda Risu and Kureiji Ollie](https://kawaentertainment.com/news/cosplay-mania-2022-to-host-ayunda-risu-and-kureiji-ollie/), Cosplay Mania 2022 has announced that it is also set to host Moona Hoshinova and Pavolia Reine. The two VTubers will participate in the event's Japanese Anime Music (JAM) Concert.

https://twitter.com/CosplayManiaPH/status/1563073892779827202

The first Indonesian VTuber to reach a million YouTube subscribers, Moona is part of Hololive Indonesia's first generation. She is known for making beautiful and functional structures in [Minecraft](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HfRyoUFBkLM), but is widely recognized for her collaborations with Hololive's [Usada Pekora](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QivLpdnBgUs&t=0s). She also has released singles such as [愛の小さな歌 (Ai no Chiisana Uta)](https://open.spotify.com/album/1ECjmO5knUIfvWdcNCyW2I) and [High Tide](https://open.spotify.com/album/012pklMkQ8zwo0TjqSl0eU).

https://twitter.com/CosplayManiaPH/status/1563089034682896388

Pavolia Reine from HoloID's second generation also has released original songs such as [Gate Open: START!](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VFpOBazE3rs), [あの青空のせいだ (Ano Aozora no Sei da)](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dzUfNQaaemk) and [Love Me Love Me](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MxwV963ZNEU). She is known for her [YABE (Yet Another Brunch, Everyone)](https://www.youtube.com/channel/UChgTyjG-pdNvxxhdsXfHQ5Q/search?query=yabe) streams.

***

Cosplay Mania happens on the weekend of October 1-2, 2022 at SMX Convention Center Manila, Pasay City, Metro Manila, Philippines. Visit [facebook.com/CosplayMania](https://www.facebook.com/CosplayMania/ "https://www.facebook.com/CosplayMania/") for more details.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former JKT48 Member Aurel Mayori Teases VTuber Model]]></title>
            <link>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/former-jk-t48-member-aurel-mayori-teases-v-tuber-model/</link>
            <guid>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/former-jk-t48-member-aurel-mayori-teases-v-tuber-model/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 16:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Aurel Mayori, formerly a member of Indonesian idol group JKT48, has recently teased about her upcoming VTuber model on her YouTube channel. In the YouTube Shorts video, she teased a rigged VTuber model, with a caption translating to “_what anime is this?_”

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y8AegmB_wZo`

YoRI, as she is familiarly called, has also posted the video on Twitter, and has invited fans to keep a closer look on her new YouTube channel regarding updates of the VTuber model.

Mayori joined JKT48 in September 2018 as a JKT48 Academy Class B Student. She was then promoted to Class A of the Academy in October 2018. She became part of JKT48’s Team J in October 2019 before being shuffled to Team T in May 2020. She announced her graduation from the group in March 2021.

Following her graduation, she started her independent singing career with the release of her first single “_Unlock._” The song was mixed by Farhan Sarasin, known for his other VTuber music mixes in Hololive Myth’s “_A Journey of a Thousand Years_” for instance.

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WMebsJ0mqNM`]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Twitch to Now Allow Partners to Stream to Rival Streaming Platforms]]></title>
            <link>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/twitch-to-now-allow-partners-to-stream-to-rival-streaming-platforms/</link>
            <guid>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/twitch-to-now-allow-partners-to-stream-to-rival-streaming-platforms/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 15:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Popular streaming platform Twitch has now announced that streamers signed into the platform as Twitch Partners can now stream to rival streaming platforms available like YouTube and Facebook Gaming. This marks one of Twitch’s biggest moves this year, effectively putting an end to its partner exclusivity clause.

Through its [FAQ page](https://help.twitch.tv/s/article/partner-exclusivity-faq?language=en_US), Twitch also encourages its streamers to also promote their Twitch livestreams on other rival platforms as well. However, Twitch clarified that they won’t allow simultaneous streams i.e. hosting your Twitch stream to rival streaming platforms. Once their Twitch stream ends, they can proceed to stream to other streaming platforms their partner is on.

The move is especially relevant for the larger VTubing community, considering the rising number of VTubers hosting their streams on the platform to get a ‘Twitch Partner’ status. In addition, Twitch remains a dominant choice of streaming service for most VTubers this year.

In the latest [Spring 2022 VTuber Census](https://www.canva.com/design/DAE9am3aIE0/diQaP3hJC2W_bknlz98L3A/view?utm_content=DAE9am3aIE0&utm_campaign=designshare&utm_medium=link&utm_source=publishsharelink) conducted by the VTuber Network, over 1,000 VTubers say that Twitch is where they most host their content creation, dwarfing other online platforms like YouTube, Twitter, and even TikTok.

_Photo by_ [_Caspar Camille Rubin_](https://unsplash.com/@casparrubin?utm_source=unsplash&utm_medium=referral&utm_content=creditCopyText) _on_ [_Unsplash_](https://unsplash.com/?utm_source=unsplash&utm_medium=referral&utm_content=creditCopyText)]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hololive Council Releases First Original Song ‘Rise’]]></title>
            <link>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/hololive-council-releases-first-original-song-rise/</link>
            <guid>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/hololive-council-releases-first-original-song-rise/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 15:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[The Hololive Council under the Hololive English branch has released their first original song titled ‘Rise’. It was released on August 24 on Hololive English’s YouTube channel, and is now available across [different streaming platforms](https://cover.lnk.to/Rise).

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jHibTDJlTJw`

This marks the Council’s first original song as a group, and was also released in commemoration of Council’s first anniversary. The song was composed by Ereca Suzuki, and Menma, with noire writing the lyrics. It is also worth noting that the song and the music video features Tsukumo Sana, who recently graduated in July.

Hololive Council is currently composed of VTubers Ceres Fauna, Ouro Kronii, Nanashi Mumei, and Hakos Baelz. All debuted on August 23, 2021, and is the second wave of Hololive English members after Hololive Myth and the launch of Project HOPE with IRyS.

_Hololive English © 2016 COVER Corp._]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aetheria Project’s Alchemilla Menace to Go On Indefinite Hiatus]]></title>
            <link>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/aetheria-project-s-alchemilla-menace-to-go-on-indefinite-hiatus/</link>
            <guid>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/aetheria-project-s-alchemilla-menace-to-go-on-indefinite-hiatus/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 15:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Alchemilla Menace from independent VTuber group Aetheria Project has announced that she will be suspending her streaming activities and go on an indefinite hiatus after her last stream, which will happen on August 26.

In a [personal statement](https://twitter.com/MAlchemilla/status/1562201190166736900) posted by Menace, she said that she is dealing more recently with stress in her real life, and that she needs to take some time off to focus on her family and take care of them.

Aetheria Project has also formally announced Menace’s indefinite hiatus, stating her donation links and Twitch subscriptions will remain open, albeit fans shouldn’t expect any content from Menace’s side.

https://twitter.com/aetheriapro/status/1562204226188877825

Aetheria Project, formerly the US-based VTuber company CyberLive, came into fruition when they debuted their first generation on July 14, 2021. The company rebranded as Aetheria on May 12, citing difficulties in terms of financial / budgetary issues, as well as continued targeted harassment of the company and its talent, according to its [press release](https://docs.google.com/document/d/e/2PACX-1vTgKKmhhE53t414X_r7xflnpsT8tIh4jZLFZz7XRG_3HMrV3Sxsi5hkJNmJnh87FfPvpzLHBhMuYJz9/pub) back then.

The current lineup for Aetheria includes Momozora Seina, Utano Pandora, Oumiya Emma, Inami Yoki, and Vera Vee, who formerly served as CyberLive’s manager. Former talents Ayane Hylo and Kurohana Inori became independent VTubers, while Amaris Yuri and Kaneko Lumi transferred to Phase-Connect.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ArkNET’s Rania Chiwawa to Graduate on August 31]]></title>
            <link>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/ark-net-s-rania-chiwawa-to-graduate-on-august-31/</link>
            <guid>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/ark-net-s-rania-chiwawa-to-graduate-on-august-31/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 15:19:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[VTuber Rania Chiwawa from Indonesian VTuber project ArkNET is set to graduate this August 31. In true fashion to her lore, Chiwawa stated that she will be ‘returning to Doggoland after learning much about humans and their technology’.

ArkNET posted their announcement of the graduation on their Twitter account, thanking Rania for her service, as well as thanking fans for the unwavering support they have received.

https://twitter.com/ArkNET_ID/status/1561707258563596288

Rania has also set up her upcoming graduation stream, which will happen at around 8PM (GMT+7). The [waiting room](http://youtu.be/eSiKCapdSTk) for the stream has been set up.

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eSiKCapdSTk`

Rania Chiwawa is one of ArkNET’s VTuber talents, aside from Raska Malendra and Enji Notokunchoro. She debuted on March 21, 2021, and has over 30,000 YouTube subscribers as of this writing. 

Following the announcement, ArkNET said that by September 1 this year, the VTuber project announced that they will be [disbanding](https://twitter.com/ArkNET_ID/status/1561707510574333952). Raska and Enji will continue as independent VTubers.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Liliana Vampaia 3D Model Fundraiser Goal Reached]]></title>
            <link>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/liliana-vampaia-3-d-model-fundraiser-goal-reached/</link>
            <guid>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/liliana-vampaia-3-d-model-fundraiser-goal-reached/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 02:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Malaysia-based MyHoloTV agency announced that the goal for Liliana Vampaia's 3D model fundraiser has been reached, 7 days before the campaign ends.

A total of US$5,040 has been [pledged](https://fundrazr.com/lilianavampaia) by 70 contributors on fundraising website FundRazr. In turn, those who pledge have the following benefits such as:

* Both online and offline live performance
* 3D version song cover release
* Virtual Photo Session with Fans
* Creating private events with Fans in a virtual world (VRChat)
* Full-body live-streaming

Proceeds from this fundraising campaign will be used to produce Liliana's 3D model and enhance her motion capture suit, as well as allocate for video editing, and live events. The tentative date of rewards is set for January 2023.

Half-human, half-vampire Liliana started her VTubing journey in June 2020 as a way to find a cure for her _Otou-san_ who was cursed to live as a bat forever after breaking rules in the vampire realm. 

She is part of MyHoloTV's MonstarZ generation alongside Lunaris Urufi, Virion Kisei and Thai VTuber HORI 07.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BanG Dream Announces Upcoming Collaboration With Hololive]]></title>
            <link>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/ban-g-dream-announces-upcoming-collaboration-with-hololive/</link>
            <guid>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/ban-g-dream-announces-upcoming-collaboration-with-hololive/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 15:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Popular mobile rhythm game _BanG Dream! Girls Band Party!_ has teased an upcoming collaboration with VTuber agency Hololive. The collaboration, according to the official English Twitter account of the game, will commence on August 26.

https://twitter.com/bangdreamgbp_EN/status/1561261824938573826

It should be noted that the announcement is posted on the game’s official English Twitter account, it is more likely that the collaboration will be only available to _BanG Dream! Girls Band Party!_ English players.

Hololive has already made a collaboration with the _BanG Dream!_ franchise back in October 2021, albeit for its Japanese players only back. The collaboration back then saw three Hololive talents: Minato Aqua, Tokino Sora, and Shirakami Fubuki–partake in the collaboration. Aside from perks and merchandise, fans also enjoyed collaboration song covers made by Hololive and the characters in-game.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[YAGOO Shows Off Summer Dance Moves in Hololive Ondo Music Video]]></title>
            <link>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/yagoo-shows-off-summer-dance-moves-in-hololive-ondo-music-video/</link>
            <guid>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/yagoo-shows-off-summer-dance-moves-in-hololive-ondo-music-video/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Motoaki Tanigo ‘YAGOO’ has shown off his summer dance moves in the music video for “_Hololive Ondo_” the second track for the Hololive Summer 2022 event.

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s_uiT5C8BjQ`

The music video was filmed at the Shin-Yokohama Ramen Museum, and features YAGOO dancing along with the well-known mascots of Oozora Subaru’s duck, Sakura Miko, and Tokino Sora’s Ankimo. Japanese musical ensemble IOSYS was responsible for the composition, arrangement and lyrics of the song.

Following the music video release, YAGOO posted on Twitter, joking that the reason why he had a serious face during the music video shoot was due to the shoot being scheduled late at night, and had to drop by after his work in the office.

https://twitter.com/tanigox/status/1561301213752479744

[Hololive Summer 2022](https://hololivesummer2022.hololivepro.com/) has also released another music video for “[_Tonde K!_](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zHD5MCUezVo)”. A special celebration held by Hololive since 2019, some of the upcoming events that will happen during this event include outdoor advertising for Hololive Summer in Shinjuki Station featuring Hololive talents in _yukata_ attire, a special web manga video series centered around the summer festivities, among others.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sony Music Entertainment Japan Teases VEE Project’s Dev-c Generation]]></title>
            <link>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/sony-music-entertainment-japan-teases-vee-project-s-dev-c-generation/</link>
            <guid>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/sony-music-entertainment-japan-teases-vee-project-s-dev-c-generation/</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 14:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Sony Music Entertainment Japan has teased the debut of a new VTuber lineup under VEE Project. The third unit, dubbed ‘Dev-c’ will debut on August 26, 2022, with each talent allotted their own debut time on said day.

Dev-c is composed of talents Aomiya Yozuri, Uriyone, Uparu, Luminous Amaama, and TwiCoto. Catch their debut schedules here:

* Aomiya Yozuri (18:00 JST)
* Uriyone (18:45 JST)
* Uparu (19:30 JST)
* Luminous Amaama (20:15 JST)
* TwiCoto (21:00 JST)

https://twitter.com/_vee_official_/status/1561556264554987521

Currently, there are two waves within the VEE Project, namely Dev-a (Otokado Ruki, Tulsi-Nightmare Madness IV, Hinahoshi Airu, Kujo Ringo, Syusetu Kohaku) and Dev-b (Audrey Mina, Oshiro Ito, Sazanami Toa, Hiyori Chihiyo, Mew Garcia, and retired talent [Shindouji Ako](https://kawaentertainment.com/news/vee-project-s-shindouji-ako-officially-retires/))

Other VTuber projects under the Sony Music Entertainment Japan brand include VERSE, Cinderella Project, and [PRISM Project](https://kawaentertainment.com/news/tag/prism/).

_Photo from VEE / Illustration:_ [_kodamazon_](https://twitter.com/kodamazon_kdm)]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hololive’s Murasaki Shion Releases New Single Chandelier]]></title>
            <link>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/hololive-s-murasaki-shion-releases-new-single-chandelier/</link>
            <guid>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/hololive-s-murasaki-shion-releases-new-single-chandelier/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 22:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Murasaki Shion from Hololive has released a new single titled _Chandelier_. The track is produced and written by popular Vocaloid producer Kanaria, known for her tracks like _KING_, _Identity,_ and _Envy Baby_.

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y-pC9U_usX8`

The track was released in commemoration of Shion’s 4th anniversary of her debut as a VTuber. The music video’s main art was illustrated by popular VTuber illustrator LAM.

This is the third single from Murasaki Shion, following her past singles “_Mage of Violet_” (August 2021) and “_AcaciaSyndrome_” (December 2021). She also appeared in other collab singles, such as “_Shiny Smily Story_” (September 2019) and “_Dreaming Days_” (February 2021).

Shion debuted as part of Hololive’s second generation, alongside Minato Aqua, Nakiri Ayame, Yuzuki Choco and Oozora Subaru. She debuted on August 17, 2019. On April 10 this year, she hit the one million subscriber milestone on YouTube.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Interview: Hanari, Hong Kong Cosplayer Recognized by Haachama]]></title>
            <link>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/interview-hanari-hong-kong-cosplayer-recognized-by-haachama/</link>
            <guid>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/interview-hanari-hong-kong-cosplayer-recognized-by-haachama/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 20:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[The Otaku Expo Tanabata Festival 2022 was recently held on the weekend of August 20-21, and it brought special guest cosplayers Hanari and Toto to the Philippines. Hanari and Toto are members of Hong Kong-based subculture group V-Project whose interest include cosplay, dance and drama performances.

Hololive's Akai Haato (Haachama) has recognized Hanari's[ cosplay](https://twitter.com/TakanashiHanari/status/1454448886949371905) and attention to detail during one of her cosplay contest streams in November 2021 (_Timestamp:_ [_1:01:05_](https://youtu.be/B0a-hm7j-ho?t=3665)), to the point of even following the cosplayer on Twitter.

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B0a-hm7j-ho&t=3665s`

[Hanari](https://www.instagram.com/takanashi_hanariv3v/) has faithfully cosplayed several VTubers from Hololive as well as Nijisanji's Hyakumantenbara Salome.[ Toto](https://www.instagram.com/toto0w0o/), on the other hand, has also cosplayed as Hololive's Amane Kanata, Momosuzu Nene and Hakui Koyori.

On this feature story, we put the spotlight on Hanari and asked her how she got into the VTuber rabbit hole, and what she felt after being recognized by one. We got her insight into VTuber cosplays as well.

_Adjustments were made in this feature story for clarity._

## How Hanari Ended Up Cosplaying Haachama

Just like any other fan, Hanari started watching VTubers upon recommendation of her friends:

"_I was recommended (VTubers) by my friends, and then I searched the name of the VTubers on YouTube. I saw the clips made by their fans, and then I got fully in-love with Haachama, Sakura Miko, Houshou Marine, and Usada Pekora from Hololive Production._"

Hanari said Haachama's cooking streams are so funny, so much so that she tried cosplaying the VTuber herself. When Haachama opened submissions for the cosplay review stream, Hanari tweeted her cosplay submission. This is how she got recognized: "_She retweeted my photos and followed me back. I'm so glad she showed my pictures on stream._"

How does it feel to be recognized by Haachama? She recalled the time she screamed in excitement and glee as she was mentioned on stream. "_I still remember that memorable moment. I'm so surprised because I've never been posted, tweeted or streamed by a VTuber in their live stream. I'm so proud of myself, and I'm glad I cosplayed her._"

For portraying Akai Haato faithfully, the VTuber told everyone: "_This is so perfect!_" Haachama even used one of her cosplay photos as thumbnails for her streams. "_One of my cosplay photos was made as a thumbnail for her stream, so I really feel proud of myself. I'm so happy, I can't control myself and I just screamed out. I also gave her a superchat after she recognized me._"

## Hanari Lures Friends Into the VTuber Rabbit Hole

![](/src/assets/content/images/img20220820143429.jpg)

_Hanari (right) signing cosplay prints during Otaku Expo Tanabata Festival 2022._

Haachama is definitely Hanari's most favorite VTuber character to cosplay, but she also loves cosplaying shrine maiden Mikochi. We asked her how she'd recommend Haachama and Mikochi to others:

"_Maybe I will send them photos of Haachama and Miko on a bed, I guess, lying beside each other. They're actually funny and they are close, showing that they're in the same boat. In conclusion, they are so cute together, so I'm trying to convince my friends to cosplay them. Maybe I can cosplay both characters myself._"

For the record, she cosplayed[ as Miko](https://www.instagram.com/p/CatSnQnBKqe/?hl=en) as a gift for the VTuber's birthday. Also, she told us that she ships Haachama and Mikochi together.

"_Recently, I love the couple of Sakura Miko and Haachama. The_ couple ship _I love the most is Sakura Miko and Haachama. They are so funny, because Haachama always cheats on Sakura Miko. They do some interesting reactions together._"

### Toto as a Good Example of Hanari’s Convincing

If she was luring her friends into the VTuber rabbit hole, does it mean that she convinced Toto to cosplay the herbivore bard Tsunomaki Watame at the event?

"_Yes, I convinced her to cosplay Watame with me, because I know Haachama and Watame are like a couple. In the very beginning when they entered Hololive, they met together and became friends, and we can see they are close. Their reactions are so fun."_

Turns out, the convincing was effective for Toto: "_I cosplayed Watame because I felt she's very, very cute, and her streams are crazy. I think I can be her, so I'm very happy (cosplaying as her)._"

## How Hanari Cosplays VTubers

Hanari has a busy cosplaying career, and we are curious how she cosplays VTubers. We went ahead and asked if she made her costumes by herself.

"_Sometimes, I would do it for myself, like some swimsuits and some underwear, some lacy stuff, I can do it by myself, like these accessories—_"

![](/src/assets/content/images/haachama-accessory.jpg)

_Left: Akai Haato's idol outfit (©2016 COVER Corp.) / Right: Hanari's accessory up-close_

As she was cosplaying Haachama's idol outfit, she showed us the heart accessory she made.

"_Because I had to cosplay so many costumes such as Haachama and other VTubers, I don't have much time to do a lot of cosplays, so I order from shops. I seldom make costumes myself, but I know how to sew too_," she further elaborated.

We go back to the time when Hanari cosplayed as Haachama eating worms: "_Maybe the easiest part is we always can see them in their YouTube channels, and we know how they behave, know their attitude or characteristics, so that we can act like them very well and do the stuff they do, such as Haachama eating worms. I can just buy some worms and act like eating it, so I can truly cosplay as Haachama._"

According to Hanari, cosplaying as VTubers can be easy or difficult depending on their presence and popularity. "_The difficult part is, maybe, there are many VTubers, so if the VTuber you love is not that famous, you may not get her costume at shops or buy it online. You may have to make it by yourself._"

Established cosplayers such as Hanari give emphasis on costume detail and character portrayal, but on top of it all, it's the sense of enjoyment that matters. Here's her advice for others who want to start cosplaying VTubers:

"_I think they should watch more clips to know more about the VTubers they love. Actually, it's easy to cosplay VTubers because there are many costumes to choose from, and there are many products or costumes they can buy at shops or online. Just have fun on your cosplay and don't worry, be proud of yourself and act like the VTuber you like._"

## Hanari's Future VTuber Cosplay Plans

It is known that Hanari is really into Akai Haato and Sakura Miko, and when we asked about her future cosplay plans, she's keen on producing a Miko photobook: "_Actually, I've been cosplaying Miko a few times, but I'm planning to do a Miko photo book this coming December. I'll sell my merchandise in Hong Kong. I really love her and I really want to present the best cosplay of her._"

***

_Thank you very much to Hanari as well as Toto for sharing their time with us. Special thanks to the organizers of Otaku Expo Tanabata Festival, the Ozine Team, for making this interview for NewsDrop possible._]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[VTubers Shoto, Bao Officially Join United Talent Agency Roster]]></title>
            <link>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/v-tubers-shoto-bao-officially-join-united-talent-agency-roster/</link>
            <guid>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/v-tubers-shoto-bao-officially-join-united-talent-agency-roster/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 13:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Independent VTubers Shoto and Bao are officially joining the talent roster of United Talent Agency (UTA), a global talent agency based in Beverly Hills, California.

According to a report from [_Dot Esports_](https://dotesports.com/streaming/news/sykkuno-kkatamina-more-join-uta-talent-agency-expands-streaming-vtuber), Shxtou and Bao join other popular streamers such as Sykkuno, Kkatamina, Buddha, and _Stranger Things_ actress Grace Van Dien. Unlike existing streamer organizations or agencies like 100Thieves and OfflineTV, UTA operates as a way to aid signed talents to find sponsorships and other promotional opportunities.

While Shoto hasn’t announced his signing with UTA, Bao had already posted about it on Twitter last June, stating that she is now represented by UTA.

https://twitter.com/baovtuber/status/1542228850083409922

Shoto debuted on October 2, 2021, and is part of an independent VTuber group called Hanamori. Meanwhile, Bao, who previously produced music under the name Hikaru Station, debuted on October 30, 2020, where she released her single “52-Hearts.”]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PRISM Project’s Naki Kamizuki Gets YouTube Channel Terminated Temporarily]]></title>
            <link>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/prism-project-s-naki-kamizuki-gets-you-tube-channel-terminated-temporarily/</link>
            <guid>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/prism-project-s-naki-kamizuki-gets-you-tube-channel-terminated-temporarily/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 12:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Naki Kamizuki, a VTuber from PRISM Project, has announced that her YouTube channel was terminated for no reason after all. The channel termination follows after Naki did a watch-along for the first three episodes of the anime series _Fuuto Pi_, albeit she has reasoned that she hasn’t shown anything on screen when her channel was terminated.

https://twitter.com/nakikamizuki/status/1560877509884817408

Following the incident, PRISM Project has stated that they are investigating YouTube’s actions regarding the channel termination, and rest assured that they will provide more information in the following days.

https://twitter.com/PRISMproj/status/1560882807097806848

Putting humor regarding the situation, Naki joked that the reason for her channel to get terminated was due to her [showing her thighs](https://twitter.com/nakikamizuki/status/1560879365545545729) on stream.

The channel is now restored after almost seven hours, but she has postponed her book club stream until they hear feedback from YouTube regarding this matter.

https://twitter.com/nakikamizuki/status/1560987689020624896

Naki Kamizuki is part of PRISM Project’s fourth generation, alongside Sara Nagare, Sumi Ushio and Non Anon. She debuted on November 13, 2021, and has recently celebrated her birthday on August 13.

PRISM Project has also stated that orders for [Naki’s birthday merchandise](https://prismproject.booth.pm/items/4076467) and voice pack will be only available up until next week. ]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Phoebe Chan Departs Shirayuri Pro to Become Independent VTuber]]></title>
            <link>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/phoebe-chan-departs-shirayuri-pro-to-become-independent-v-tuber/</link>
            <guid>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/phoebe-chan-departs-shirayuri-pro-to-become-independent-v-tuber/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 07:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[VTuber Phoebe Chan from US-based VTuber project Shirayuri Pro has announced her departure from the group to become a fully independent VTuber. The announcement was first made during the VTuber group’s second-year anniversary stream.

According to a statement she posted on Twitter, her departure takes effect on September 1, and has encouraged fans to look forward to her re-debut and birthday celebration on October 28.

https://twitter.com/feebeechanchibi/status/1560814330584543232

“Going forward, I intend to focus mainly on my singing and music, convention performances, and appearances, and growing my voice acting career. To clarify, however, I will not be graduating as Phoebe, nor will I be ceasing my VTubing activities,” she stated.

Phoebe Chan, also known by her moniker as ‘Feebeechanchibi’, describes herself as a ‘2.5D singer and voice actress’. Aside from her VTubing career, she has also devoted her time to creating original music and performing in the idol group PhEri. She recently released her second original single “_Symphonic Sky_”, which was released on April 29 this year.

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PglmGP__xrM`

Some of her other music-related releases include her first original solo EP, _Moon Garden_ (March 2020), and _Chill Bee-Ts to Buzz to_ (April 2021).]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Multiverse Monarch Releases Music Video for Metamorphosis]]></title>
            <link>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/multiverse-monarch-releases-music-video-for-metamorphosis/</link>
            <guid>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/multiverse-monarch-releases-music-video-for-metamorphosis/</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 06:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Multiverse Monarch, the VTuber persona of American voice actress and singer Amanda Lee (AmaLee), has released a music video for her track “_Metamorphosis_”. The song is the third track of her first original album under her Monarch VTuber persona titled _Rise of the Monarch_.

`youtube:https://youtu.be/9JK30m32Dvg`

Monarch has also released music videos for other tracks in the Rise of the Monarch album, including “[_From The Embers_](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y3TdeNWwniQ&t=0s)”, “[_Drink Your Light_](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QbAOizRHKxs&t=0s)”, and “[_Villain Vibes_](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kFaie-Tp1Jw&t=0s)” featuring Hololive English’s Mori Calliope. _Rise of the Monarch_ was [released digitally](https://ffm.to/RiseoftheMonarch) on June 24. Fans can also pre-order a physical copy of her album on her [official website](https://shop.leeandlie.com/products/rise-of-the-monarch-cd), estimated to be shipped around September.

AmaLee debuted her Monarch VTuber persona on December 11, 2021. Outside of her VTuber work, she is known for her English cover songs of popular anime tracks, as well as providing vocals independent video game soundtracks and theme songs. One of her most notable song contributions was for the track “_Fellow Feeling_” by American DJ/producer Porter Robinson, which was included in his first album “_Worlds_” in 2014.

AmaLee has also provided voice acting roles for English dubs of several anime titles such as _Kaguya-sama: Love Is War_, _My Dress-Up Darling_, _SSSS.Dynazenon_, _Kageki Shojo!!_, _Girls' Frontline_, _Odd Taxi_, among others.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AniManGaki 2022 to Showcase 80 Malaysian VTubers]]></title>
            <link>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/ani-man-gaki-2022-to-showcase-80-malaysian-v-tubers/</link>
            <guid>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/ani-man-gaki-2022-to-showcase-80-malaysian-v-tubers/</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 06:55:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[The annual AniManGaki convention is back in action, and it brings a newly-launched section on VTubers. A total of 80 Malaysian VTubers, independent and agency-affiliated, will be featured in this year's event.

https://twitter.com/animangaki/status/1560281935162662912

https://twitter.com/animangaki/status/1560281947208790017

https://twitter.com/animangaki/status/1560281958592106496

Featured VTubers include Aetheria Project's Oumiya Emma, Phase Connect's Remilia Nephys, Live2D artist Momoiro Kohi, Sushiya, and Valyria Starfire.

This VTuber Showcase will happen at the Upper Mezzanine Floor of AniManGaki 2022 inside Mines International Exhibition Centre, Selangor, Malaysia on the weekend of August 27-28. Tickets are available at [animangaki.com](https://www.animangaki.com/).

_Photo from_ [_AniManGaki Twitter_](https://twitter.com/animangaki/status/1560281935162662912)]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mori Calliope Releases Music Video for Let’s End The World]]></title>
            <link>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/mori-calliope-releases-music-video-for-let-s-end-the-world/</link>
            <guid>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/mori-calliope-releases-music-video-for-let-s-end-the-world/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Popular Hololive English VTuber Mori Calliope has released a music video for her track “_Let’s End The World_”. The song is produced by Vocaloid producer Giga-P and popular Japanese music producer TeddyLoid.

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=etW-seMBfeE`

_Let’s End The World_ is the last track of Mori Calliope’s _SHINIGAMI_ _NOTE_ EP, the first extended playlist collection Calliope released as part of her record label deal with Universal Music Group and EMI Records.

The latest update comes weeks after Calliope held her first-ever major solo concert “_New Underworld Order_”, last July 21 at the Toyosu PIT live music venue in Tokyo.

Calliope remains as the Hololive English member with the most number of original song and album releases. Her past EP releases include “_DEAD BEATS_” (October 2020), “_Your Mori_” (April 2021), as well as her first album “_UnAlive_” (March 2022). She is also known for her single tracks such as “_Off With Their Heads_”, “_end of a life_”, “_cursed night_”, as well as her collaboration tracks like “_Villain_” with AmaLee, “_Graveyard Shift_” with BOOGEY VOXX, and “_YONA YONA JOURNEY_” with Taku Inoue.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nijisanji’s Lie:verse Liars Mixed Media Project Releases First Novel Serialization]]></title>
            <link>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/nijisanji-s-lie-verse-liars-mixed-media-project-releases-first-novel-serialization/</link>
            <guid>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/nijisanji-s-lie-verse-liars-mixed-media-project-releases-first-novel-serialization/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 21:52:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[_Lie:verse Liars_—a mixed media project by VTuber agency Nijisanji, media conglomerate KADOKAWA, and graphic design company BALCOLONY—has revealed the first release from the project, a light novel titled “_Lie:verse Liars: How to Start a Bad End That Will Make Us Happy._”

The novel is penned down by Japanese light novelist Kazuma Ōtorino, and is currently serialized on [_MF Bunko_](https://kakuyomu.jp/works/16817139556423430612).

The _Lie:verse Liars_ mixed media project incorporates several Nijisanji VTubers as characters in the story, and each have their own voice actors being cast for future projects. The main cast includes Kana Sukoya as Saki Himekawa, Alice Mononobe as Stella, Eru as Hana Fuwa, Lize Helesta as Yuragi Kigsu, voice actors Takahide Ishii as Meguru Tokitoh, and Taku Yashiro as Ruu Haizura.

As part of the project, which was launched on July 8 this year, a promotional trailer was released:

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FAKYeQ_CdRE`

_Lie:verse Liars_ is expected to expand its media release into several media such as an anime adaptation and a manga series.

_Source:_ [_PRTimes_](https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000483.000030865.html)]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nijisanji’s Axia Krone Goes on Indefinite Hiatus Following Targeted Online Slander]]></title>
            <link>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/nijisanji-s-axia-krone-goes-on-indefinite-hiatus-following-targeted-online-slander/</link>
            <guid>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/nijisanji-s-axia-krone-goes-on-indefinite-hiatus-following-targeted-online-slander/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 21:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Axia Krone from Nijisanji's Eden-gumi group is going on an indefinite hiatus following reports of constant slander and targeted online harassment against him on-stream.

In a [statement](https://www.anycolor.co.jp/news/ptphttmlev) posted by parent company ANYCOLOR, the hiatus was made following Axia’s wishes to take a break, as the negative comments have affected not only the talent’s physical and mental health, but also other talents around him.

ANYCOLOR has stressed in their statement that the online harassment has greatly affected their livestream distribution, and that they would not tolerate such fan behavior to carry on across their online channels.

The company also added that following these negative events, they are filing criminal charges against online users who have spread such malicious information regarding Krone and other talents.

“We have already started concrete legal measures to deal with the malicious business obstruction and infringement of goodwill against our business in cooperation with our legal advisory firm and the police,” ANYCOLOR stated.

In addition, the company has already identified certain websites that are promoting such negative statements targeted towards their talents. It has also encouraged the public to report to them if they see any forms of targeted harassment against their talents moving forward.

Krone released two videos before proceeding with his indefinite hiatus, the first is [a video](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PGvMKhAHEGw) addressing possessive fans, and the second is a diss track.

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wkOciDA_WRA`

Axia Krone debuted alongside his Eden-gumi colleagues Lauren Iroas, Leos Vincent, Oliver Evans, and Lain Paterson. He debuted on July 22, 2021.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Haven-X Disbands Following Graduation of Its Talents]]></title>
            <link>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/haven-x-disbands-following-graduation-of-its-talents/</link>
            <guid>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/haven-x-disbands-following-graduation-of-its-talents/</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[VTuber agency Haven-X has announced on Twitter that their talents Koa Himari and Viri Sylvaine have graduated as of August 17, 2022. They followed another talent, Roza Coatl, who [graduated July 11](https://twitter.com/havenx_official/status/1559902903661301760) due to health concerns. 

https://twitter.com/havenx_official/status/1559902903661301760

In addition, Haven-X management said that Both Koa and Viri have declined to hold a graduation stream. As a result, Haven-X disbands following graduation of its talents.

YouTube memberships for all graduated talents will be closed by 11:59:59 PM JST on Monday, October 31.

In a [separate tweet](https://twitter.com/junjun585858/status/1559907694555045888), Yoojun Kang, CEO of Still Green, Inc. which handles the agency, thanked everyone who has supported Haven-X, and apologized that they had to make this announcement.

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l-4ppZVtnBE`

Haven-X was first [introduced](https://news.qoo-app.com/en/post/80997/haven-x-productions-metaverse-vtuber) as the world's first VTuber project dedicated to the metaverse, and the talents are referred to as "metaverse idols." The initial plan for its future development was "to provide a completely new entertainment experience with the use of technology, such as NFTs, blockchains, and the metaverse."]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[VTuber Design Book at Comiket 100 Sold Out]]></title>
            <link>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/v-tuber-design-book-at-comiket-100-sold-out/</link>
            <guid>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/v-tuber-design-book-at-comiket-100-sold-out/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 17:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[The 100th edition of Japan's popular Comic Market (Comiket) happened just last weekend, and among the various books sold at the fan event of the summer is a **VTuber Design Book** featuring more than 800 assets for various VTuber activities created by 98 designers.

`youtube:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XEDNIRzuRrA`

The book is divided into three parts: Design Samples, Design Wisdom and Design Materials, all done with a vision to improve the quality of VTuber designs in general. Physical copies of the book sold out at Comiket 100 in just a few hours.

[https://twitter.com/kurumi_mokoko/status/1558297759568261120](https://twitter.com/kurumi_mokoko/status/1558297759568261120 "https://twitter.com/kurumi_mokoko/status/1558297759568261120")

A total of 245 supporters backed the project on [Campfire](https://camp-fire.jp/projects/view/582411) for a total of around 1.2 million yen, which 305% of its 400,000-yen goal. The digital version is still available on [BOOTH](https://obakeshop.booth.pm/items/4067634) and [Melonbooks](https://www.melonbooks.co.jp/detail/detail.php?product_id=1595385).

Photo: [Okuri Sae on Twitter](https://twitter.com/OkuriSae/status/1559004795586748417)]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[VEE Project’s Shindouji Ako Officially Retires]]></title>
            <link>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/vee-project-s-shindouji-ako-officially-retires/</link>
            <guid>https://kawaentertainment.com/news/vee-project-s-shindouji-ako-officially-retires/</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 06:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[Shindouji Ako, a VTuber that is part of Sony Music Entertainment Japan’s VEE Project, has retired from her official VTuber activities, a month after she debuted.

In an [announcement](https://vee-official.jp/news/220812_shindouji-retirement/) from the VEE Project, the agency said that Ako has decided to retire due to concerns about her poor health condition. The agency added that while they have discussed the possibility of temporarily suspending her activities, the talent has decided to retire from her activities, which the agency respects.

Prior to the announcement on August 12, Shindouji Ako posted an update on July 24 that she hasn’t been active since her debut stream, and that she is consulting with her doctor regarding her health condition, albeit unspecified.

https://twitter.com/Ako_shindouji/status/1550892708923064320

Shindouji Ako, alongside the second wave of VEE Project talents Audrey Mina, Oshiro Ito, Sazanami Toa, Hiyori Chihiyo, and Mew Garcia–debuted on July 3. Following her retirement, the agency has stated that all of her social media channels will remain up.]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>